# DIEGO LÓPEZ TAMAYO

Mexico City ♦ 03300

(+52) 5539526930  $\Leftrightarrow$  diego.lopez@colmex.mx  $\Leftrightarrow$  diego-eco.github.io

Economist with experience in program evaluation, applied microeconomics, industrial organization, and applied econometrics. Interested in regulation and competition in digital markets, digital economy and labour markets. Data analysis and visualization skills. Passionate about using economic tools to promote development and reduce inequality in our society.

## **EDUCATION**

# El Colegio de México (Colmex)

August 2019 - June 2021\*

Master in Economics. Department of Economics CEE.

Thesis: Pricing in Bilateral Markets: Hedonic Pricing Analysis for Airbnb in CDMX

## University of Warwick, UK

January 2018 - July 2018

Academic exchange program.

Courses: Time Series, Industrial Organization and Labour Economics.

## Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México (UNAM)

August 2014 - June 2019

Bachelor in Economics (with honors).

Thesis: Ride-sharing platforms in Mexico City: Economic theory and empirical evidence.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### International Business Research Groningen

April 2019 - July 2019

Local Consultant for IBR 2019 Mexico - University of Groningen.

Market study and analysis for the Mexican dairy sector. www.ibr-groningen.nl

#### Center for Economic Research on Innovation (CEPCyT)

January 2016 - December 2018

Research assistant for Dr. Leonel Corona Treviño.

Topics: economic innovation, entrepreneurship and economic theory. www.cepcyt.org

#### TEACHING EXPERIENCE

#### Faculty of Economics UNAM

January 2017 - December 2018

TA in Mathematics for Economics. Undergraduate level. Professor. Araceli Borja Rodriguez.

TA in Innovation and Technological Change. Undergraduate level. Professor. Leonel Corona Trevino.

#### El Colegio de México (Colmex)

August - December 2020

TA in Game Theory. Undergraduate level. Professor. Julen Berasaluce Iza.

#### LANGUAGES AND SOFTWARE SKILLS

Laguages Spanish (native). English (TOEFL iBT). French (DELF B2).

Modeling and Analysis R (DataViz, Shiny Apps), Stata, Python (Network Analysis)

Software & Tools MS Office, LATEX, Git, Adobe Suite.